[
    {
        "question": "How much time has passed since the Last Glacial Maximum?",
        "a": "50,000 years",
        "b": "10,000 years",
        "c": "75,000 years",
        "d": "100,000 years",
        "e": "20,000 years",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Early Harappan phase began CLOSEST to the",
        "a": "collapse of the glacial Laurentide Ice Sheet",
        "b": "fall of the Shang Dynasty",
        "c": "development of writing in Egypt",
        "d": "rise of the Akkadian Empire",
        "e": "earliest recorded Homo sapiens fossils",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following powers had the SHORTEST rule?",
        "a": "the Chavín Civilization",
        "b": "the Akkadian Empire",
        "c": "the Olmec Civilization",
        "d": "the Shang Dynasty",
        "e": "the Zhou Dynasty",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which severe climate event MOST likely occurred in Eurasia 4,250 years ago?",
        "a": "heatwaves",
        "b": "dust storms",
        "c": "floods",
        "d": "monsoons",
        "e": "drought",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Late Holocene was also called the",
        "a": "Greenlandian Age",
        "b": "Neolithic Age",
        "c": "Paleolithic Age",
        "d": "Meghalayan Age",
        "e": "Northgrippian Age",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which year do many historians label as the “worst year to be alive”? ",
        "a": "323 BCE",
        "b": "536 CE",
        "c": "1280 CE",
        "d": "476 CE",
        "e": "256 BCE",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long did the Wolf solar minimum last?",
        "a": "50 years",
        "b": "70 years",
        "c": "100 years",
        "d": "20 years",
        "e": "30 years",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which invention did scientists create in 1714?",
        "a": "the Gregorian telescope",
        "b": "the microscope",
        "c": "the barometer",
        "d": "the steam engine",
        "e": "the mercury thermometer",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following events occurred in the 1950s EXCEPT the",
        "a": "International GeoPhysical Year",
        "b": "launch of the Sputnik satellite",
        "c": "founding of NASA",
        "d": "start of the Anthropocene",
        "e": "beginning of the Cold War",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Great Acceleration started in the same year as the",
        "a": "establishment of the World Meteorological Association",
        "b": "emergence of the field of Earth System Science",
        "c": "adoption of the Paris Agreement",
        "d": "ratification of the Kyoto Protocol",
        "e": "founding of the Global Atmospheric Research Program",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which environmental science text did Rachel Carson publish in 1962?",
        "a": "Collapse",
        "b": "Cadillac Desert",
        "c": "The Diversity of Life",
        "d": "Silent Spring",
        "e": "The Sixth Extinction",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which initiative preceded the World Climate Programme?",
        "a": "the Advisory Group on Greenhouse Gases",
        "b": "the Global Atmospheric Research Program",
        "c": "the International Geosphere-Biosphere Programme",
        "d": "the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change",
        "e": "the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did the United Nations hold the Conference on Environment and Development in 1992?",
        "a": "Toronto, Canada",
        "b": "Paris, France",
        "c": "Beijing, China",
        "d": "Rio de Janeiro, Brazil",
        "e": "Villach, Austria",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following events happened LAST?",
        "a": "The United states S withdrew from the Paris Agreement.",
        "b": "The United States passed the Byrd-Hagel resolution.",
        "c": "The Fridays for Future movement began.",
        "d": "The United Nations held the Climate Change Conference.",
        "e": "The Dakota Access Pipeline sparked protests.",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who signed the Inflation Reduction Act into law?",
        "a": "Bill Clinton",
        "b": "Barack Obama",
        "c": "Joe Biden",
        "d": "Donald Trump",
        "e": "George W. Bush",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    }
]
